Chandler, Alfred D., 1918-2007. Papers, 1941-2004: A Finding Aid
Alfred D. Chandler papers, 1940-2007
- Series III. Harvard Business School (HBS), Active Tenure, 1968-1991
  - Subseries E. HBS Teaching Records, 1970-1989
    This subseries consists of materials kept Alfred Chandler documenting his teaching activities at Harvard Business School. Seminars and courses include: “The Evolution of American Business Enterprise (1970)”, “The History of Large-Scale Business Enterprise”, “The Rise of Managerial Capitalism: The World”, “The Coming of Managerial Capitalism: The World”, “The Development of the Modern Corporation in International Perspective”, “Competition and Industry Structure”, “Technology, Competition and Industry Structure”, “Innovation, Public Policy, and Industrial Structure”, “Business in its Historical Environment”, and “The Coming of Managerial Capitalism: The U.S.”
    The material consists of lecture notes, class outlines, syllabi, reading lists, exam questions, transparencies, photocopied and reprinted class material, and photocopies of Chandler's works-in-progress used for classes. These are frequently annotated. This subseries also includes a group of cases, 1972-1983 written by others but annotated by Chandler; and cases written by Chandler including notes, drafts, and revisions.
    - Faculty Seminar, Fall 1970 (Box 139, f. 1-3)
    - Business History Seminar: Course Description, 1971-1974 (Box 139, f. 4)
    - Business History Seminar: Syllabus, Spring 1971 (Box 139, f. 5)
    - Business History Seminar: Lecture Notes, Spring 1971 (Box 139, f. 6)
    - Business History Seminar: Exams, Spring, 1971 (Box 139, f. 7)
    - Business History Seminar: Reading List, Lecture Notes, Fall 1971 (Box 139, f. 8)
    - Business History Course: Syllabus, Fall 1971 (Box 139, f. 9)
    - Business History Course: Intro to RRs, Oct. 1971 (Box 139, f. 10)
    - Business History Course: Rise of Big Business, Nov. 10, 1971 (Box 139, f. 11)
    - Business History Course, Dec. 6,7,8, 1971 (Box 139, f. 12)
    - Business History Course, Dec. 10, 1971 (Box 139, f. 13)
    - Business History Course, Dec. 13, 1971 (Box 139, f. 14)
    - Business History Course: Syllabus, Fall 1972 (Box 139, f. 15)
    - Business History Course: Franklin, Sept. 18, 1972 (Box 139, f. 16)
    - Business History Course: Evaluation of Enterprise, Sept. 20, 1972 (Box 139, f. 17)
    - Business History Course: Astor, Sept. 25, 26, 1972 (Box 139, f. 18)
    - Business History Course: N. Y. Port, Sept. 26, 1972 (Box 139, f. 19)
    - Business History Course: RR, Intro, Oct. 17, 18, 1972 (Box 139, f. 20)
    - Business History Course: Railroad Management, including 1971 notes, Fall 1972 (Box 139, f. 21)
    - Business History Course, Oct. 24, 25, 1972 (Box 139, f. 22)
    - Business History Course: Morgan, Oct. 25, 1972 (Box 139, f. 23)
    - Business History Course: Beginning of Big Business, Oct. 30, 31, 1972 (Box 139, f. 24)
    - Business History Course: Evaluation of Enterprise, Nov. 7, 1972 (Box 139, f. 25)
    - Business History Course: DuPont, Dec. 11, 12, 1972 (Box 140, f. 1)
    - Business History Course: Conglomerate, Dec. 20, 1972 (Box 140, f. 2)
    - Business History Course: Spread of Multidivisional, Fall 1972 (Box 140, f. 3)
    - Business History Seminar: Syllabus, Exams, etc, Spring 1973 (Box 140, f. 4)
    - Business History Seminar: Intro, Jan. 16, 1973 (Box 140, f. 5)
    - Business History Seminar: Robber Barons, Jan. 23, 1973 (Box 140, f. 6)
    - Business History Seminar: The Merchant, Jan. 30, 1973 (Box 140, f. 7)
    - Business History Seminar: Industry, Feb. 13, 1973 (Box 140, f. 8)
    - Business History Seminar: Industry, Feb. 20, 1973 (Box 140, f. 9)
    - Business History Seminar: Finance, Feb. 27, 1973 (Box 140, f. 10)
    - Business History Seminar: Giant Enterprise, March 6, 1973 (Box 140, f. 11)
    - Business History Seminar, March 20, 1973 (Box 140, f. 12)
    - Business History Seminar: Multi-national, April 3, 1973 (Box 140, f. 13)
    - Business History Seminar, April 10, 1973 (Box 140, f. 14)
    - Business History Seminar, April 17, 1973 (Box 140, f. 15)
    - Business History Seminar, April 24, 1973 (Box 140, f. 16)
    - Business History Seminar, May 1, 1973 (Box 140, f. 17)
    - Colloquium: Harvard College: "Introduction to the Eisenhower Papers," 1973 (Box 140, f. 18)
    - Business History Course: Railroads, Spring/Fall 1973 (Box 140, f. 19)
    - Business History Course: Syllabus, Fall 1973 (Box 140, f. 20)
    - Business History Seminar: Syllabus, Fall 1973 (Box 140, f. 21)
    - Business History Seminar: Intro, Sept, 11, 1973 (Box 140, f. 22)
    - Business History Seminar: Management, Oct. 2, 1973 (Box 140, f. 23)
    - Business History Seminar: Mass Production, Fall 1973 (Box 140, f. 24)
    - Business History Seminar: Industry, Oct. 16, 1973 (Box 140, f. 25)
    - Business History Seminar: Finance, Oct. 23, 1973 (Box 140, f. 26)
    - Business History Seminar: Entrepreneurial to Managerial, Oct. 30, 1973 (Box 140, f. 27)
    - Business History Seminar: Organization Building, Nov. 6, 1973 (Box 140, f. 28)
    - Business History Seminar: Multi-industrial, Nov. 13, 1973 (Box 140, f. 29)
    - Business History Seminar, Nov. 27, 1973 (Box 140, f. 30)
    - Business History Seminar, Dec. 4, 1973 (Box 140, f. 31)
    - Business History Seminar, Nov. 20, 1973 (Box 140, f. 32)
    - Business History Supplement to Readings, 1973 (Box 140, f. 33)
    - Business History Seminar, circa 1973 (Box 140, f. 34-36)
    - History Dept. Seminar, May 10, 1973 (Box 140, f. 37)
    - Business History Course: Merchants, Sept. 17, 1973 (Box 140, f. 38)
    - EAM Course Outline, Spring 1974 (Box 140, f. 39)
    - Business History Course Matters, 1974-1976 (Box 141, f. 1)
    - Business History Seminar, 1975-1976 (Box 141, f. 2)
    - Business History Course Matters, 1975-1976 (Box 141, f. 3)
    - Business History Seminar: Class Material-The Rise of Managerial Capitalism, Spring 1976 (Box 141, f. 4-5)
    - Business History Seminar: Photographs of social event, Spring 1976 (Box 141, f. 6)
    - Business History Seminar: Exams, etc., 1976 (Box 141, f. 7)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 7, 1976 (Box 141, f. 8)
    - Business History Seminar: Merchants, Jan. 14, 1976 (Box 141, f. 9)
    - Business History Seminar: The Railroads, Jan. 20, 1976 (Box 141, f. 10)
    - Business History Seminar: Jay Gould, Jan. 26, 1976 (Box 141, f. 11)
    - Business History Seminar: Mass Marketing, Feb. 10, 1976 (Box 141, f. 12)
    - Business History Seminar: Mass Production, Feb. 17, 1976 (Box 141, f. 13)
    - Business History Seminar: Integrated Industrial Enterprise, Feb. 24, 1976 (Box 141, f. 14)
    - Business History Seminar: Finance, March 2, 1976 (Box 141, f. 15)
    - Business History Seminar: Growth of the Firm, March 9, 1976 (Box 141, f. 16)
    - Business History Seminar: Multinationals, March 16, 1976 (Box 141, f. 17)
    - Business History Seminar: Great Britain, April 6, 1976 (Box 141, f. 18)
    - Business History Seminar: Japan, April 13, 1976 (Box 141, f. 19)
    - Business History Seminar: USSR, April 20, 1976 (Box 141, f. 20)
    - Business History Seminar: Conclusion, April 27, 1976 (Box 141, f. 21)
    - Business History Course: Exams, 1976-1979 (Box 141, f. 22)
    - Business History Course: Syllabus, etc., Fall 1976 - Business in its Historical Environment (Box 141, f. 23)
    - Business History Course: Intro/Franklin, Sept. 9, 1976 (Box 141, f. 24)
    - Business History Course: Forging a National Economy, Sept. 13, 1976 (Box 141, f. 25)
    - Business History Course: Bank of U.S., Sept. 21, 1976 (Box 141, f. 26)
    - Business History Course: Coming of Industrial Corporation, Oct. 18, 1976 (Box 141, f. 27)
    - Business History Course: Mass Production, Nov. 1, 2, 1976 (Box 141, f. 28)
    - Business History Course: Mass Marketing, Nov. 8, 1976 (Box 141, f. 29)
    - Business History Course, Nov. 23, 24, 1976 (Box 141, f. 30)
    - Eliot House Course, March 1, 1976 (also Leverett House Talk) (Box 141, f. 31)
    - Business History Seminar: Introduction, Syllabus, etc., Jan. 5, 1977 (Box 141, f. 32)
    - Business History Seminar: Railroads, Jan 18, 25, 1977 (Box 141, f. 33)
    - Business History Seminar: Mass Marketing, Feb. 1, 1977 (Box 141, f. 34)
    - Business History Seminar: Mass Production, Feb. 8, 1977 (Box 141, f. 35)
    - Business History Seminar: The Industrial Corporation/Capital Markets, Feb. 15, 22, 1977 (Box 141, f. 36)
    - Business History Seminar: Modern Structure Achieved, March 1, 1977 (Box 142, f. 1)
    - Business History Seminar: Growth of the Firm, March 8, 1977 (Box 142, f. 2)
    - Business History Seminar: Multinationals, March 14, 1977 (Box 142, f. 3)
    - Business History Seminar: Britain #1, April 5, 1977 (Box 142, f. 4)
    - Business History Seminar: Britain #2, April 12, 1977 (Box 142, f. 5)
    - Business History Seminar: Japan, April 19, 1977 (Box 142, f. 6)
    - Business History Seminar: USSR, April 26, 1977 (Box 142, f. 7)
    - Business History Course: Syllabus, etc., Fall 1977 (Box 142, f. 8)
    - Business History Course, Nov. 21, 1977 (Box 142, f. 9)
    - Business History Course: DuPont, Nov. 28, 1977 (Box 142, f. 10)
    - Business History Seminar: Syllabus, etc., Spring 1978 (Box 142, f. 11)
    - Business History Seminar: Class Material, Spring 1978 (Box 142, f. 12-16)
    - Business History Course: Revisions for, 1978 (Box 142, f. 17)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 10, 1978 (Box 142, f. 18)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 17, 1978 (Box 142, f. 19)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 24, 1978 (Box 142, f. 20)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 31, 1978 (Box 142, f. 21)
    - Business History Seminar, Feb. 7, Feb. 14, 1978 (Box 142, f. 22)
    - Business History Seminar, March 7, 1978 (Box 142, f. 23)
    - Business History Seminar, March 21, 1978 (Box 142, f. 24)
    - Business History Seminar, April 25, 1978 (Box 142, f. 25)
    - Business History Course, Oct. 30, Nov. 1, 1978 (Box 142, f. 26)
    - Business History Course: Syllabus, etc.: Business in its Historical Environment, Fall 1979 (Box 143, f. 1)
    - Business History Course: Astor/Port of N.Y., Sept. 1979 (Box 143, f. 2)
    - Business History Course: N.Y. Port, Sept. 17, 1979 (Box 143, f. 3)
    - Business History Course: Standard Oil, Oct. 22, 1979 (Box 143, f. 4)
    - Business History Course: Modern Indus. Corporation, Oct. 16, 1979 (Box 143, f. 5)
    - Business History Course: Mass Production, Oct. 30, 1979 (Box 143, f. 6)
    - Business History Course: Multinational Conglomerates, Dec. 4, 1979 (Box 143, f. 7)
    - Business History Course, Dec. 5, 1979 (Box 143, f. 8)
    - Business History Course: Midterms, 1979-1981 (Box 143, f. 9)
    - Marglin Seminar, March 18, 1980 (Box 143, f. 10)
    - Business History Course: The Coming of Management Capitalism: The U.S.: Syllabus, Fall 1980 (Box 143, f. 11)
    - Business History Course: Intro: Merchants, Sept. 4, 1980 (Box 143, f. 12)
    - Business History Course, Sept. 8, 10, 1980 (Box 143, f. 13)
    - Business History Course: Finance, Sept. 29, 1980 (Box 143, f. 14)
    - Business History Course: Railroads, Fall 1980 (Box 143, f. 15)
    - Business History Course: Economic Revolution, Fall 1980 (Box 143, f. 16)
    - Business History Course: Industrial Revolution Completed, Oct. 20, 27, 1980 (Box 143, f. 17)
    - Business History Course, Dec. 8, 9, 1980 (Box 143, f. 18)
    - Business History Seminar: Notes, Spring 1980 (Box 143, f. 19)
    - Business History Seminar: Class Material, Spring 1981 (Box 143, f. 20-21)
    - Business History Seminar: Syllabus, Spring 1981 (Box 143, f. 22)
    - Business History Seminar: Intro, Jan. 6, 1981 (Box 143, f. 23)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan 13, 1981 (Box 143, f. 24)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 20, 1981 (Box 143, f. 25)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan 26, 1981 (Box 143, f. 26)
    - Business History Seminar: U.K., Feb. 3, 1981 (Box 143, f. 27)
    - Business History Seminar: Germany/France, Feb. 24, March 3, 1981 (Box 143, f. 28)
    - Business History Seminar: Continental Europe, March 10, 1981 (Box 143, f. 29)
    - Business History Seminar: Europe/Japan, March 17, 1981 (Box 143, f. 30)
    - Business History Seminar: Japan, March 24, 1981 (Box 144, f. 1)
    - Business History Seminar: Japan/USSR, April 7, 1981 (Box 144, f. 2)
    - Business History Seminar: USSR/China/Japan, April 1981 (Box 144, f. 3-4)
    - Business History Course: Syllabus, Fall 1981 (Box 144, f. 5)
    - Business History Course: Intro, Sept. 19, 1981 (Box 144, f. 6)
    - Business History Course, Sept. 14, 1981 (Box 144, f. 7)
    - Business History Course: Railroad, Sept. 28, 29, 1981 (Box 144, f. 8)
    - Business History Course: Finance, Oct. 5, 6, 1981 (Box 144, f. 9)
    - Business History Course: Mass Production, Oct. 19, 1981 (Box 144, f. 10)
    - Business History Course: Economic Revolution #1, Oct. 20, 1981 (Box 144, f. 11)
    - Business History Course: Multinational Conglomerates, Nov. 30, Dec. 1, 1981 (Box 144, f. 12)
    - Business History Course, Dec. 7, 8, 1981 (Box 144, f. 13)
    - Business History Course, 1981, 1983 (Box 144, f. 14)
    - Business History Course: Revisions, 1982-1983, undated (Box 144, f. 15)
    - Business History Seminar: Exams, etc., 1982 (Box 144, f. 16)
    - Business History Seminar: Class Material, 1982 (Box 144, f. 17-20)
    - Business History Seminar, Feb. 10, 1983 (Box 144, f. 21)
    - Business History Seminar: Organizing Session, Jan. 6, 1982 (Box 144, f. 22)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 12, 1982 (Box 144, f. 23)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 19, 1982 (Box 144, f. 24)
    - Business History Seminar: U.S., Jan. 26, 1982 (Box 144, f. 25)
    - Business History Seminar: U.S., Feb. 2, 1982 (Box 144, f. 26)
    - Business History Seminar: U.K., Feb. 9, 1982 (Box 144, f. 27)
    - Business History Seminar: U.K.. Feb. 23, 1982 (Box 144, f. 28)
    - Business History Seminar: Germany, March 2, 1982 (Box 145, f. 1)
    - Business History Seminar: Japan, March 23, 1982 (Box 145, f. 2)
    - Business History Seminar: USSR/Japan, April 13, 1982 (Box 145, f. 3)
    - Business History Seminar: USSR/Final Paper, April 20, 1982 (Box 145, f. 4)
    - Business History Seminar: Last Class, April 27, 1982 (Box 145, f. 5)
    - Seminar: The Emergence of Managerial Capitalism, April 13, 1983 (Box 145, f. 6)
    - Business History Course: Syllabus, etc., Fall 1983 (Box 145, f. 7)
    - Multinational Enterprise: Lecture Notes, 1983 (Box 145, f. 8)
    - Business History Course: Alexander Hamilton, Sept. 12, 1983 (Box 145, f. 9)
    - Business History Course, Nov. 18, 1983 (Box 145, f. 10)
    - Business History Course: Antitrust, Nov. 14, 1983 (Box 145, f. 11)
    - Business History Course: Depression, Nov. 15, 1983 (Box 145, f. 12)
    - Business History Course: Regulation, Nov. 21, 1983 (Box 145, f. 13)
    - Business History Course: Full Employment, Nov. 22, 1983 (Box 145, f. 14)
    - Business History Course: FTC Case, Nov. 23, 1983 (Box 145, f. 15)
    - Business History Course: DuPont, Nov. 28, 1983 (Box 145, f. 16)
    - Business History Course: Multinational, Nov. 29, 1983 (Box 145, f. 17)
    - Business History Course: Conglomerates/Royal Little, Dec. 5, 1983 (Box 145, f. 18)
    - Business History Course: Multinational Conglomerates, Dec. 5, 1983 (Box 145, f. 19)
    - Business History Course: Conglomerates, Dec. 6, 1983 (Box 145, f. 20)
    - Business History Course, Dec. 7, 1983 (Box 145, f. 21)
    - Business History Course: Material on Conglomerates, 1982-1983 (Box 145, f. 22)
    - Business History Seminar: Coming of Managerial Capitalism: The World, Spring 1984 (Box 145, f. 23)
    - Business History Seminar: Coming of Managerial Capitalism: The World #2, Feb. 7, 1984 (Box 145, f. 24)
    - Business History Seminar: U.S./U.K, Feb. 21, 1984 (Box 145, f. 25)
    - Business History Seminar: U.K./Germany/France, March 5, 1984 (Box 145, f. 26)
    - Business History Seminar: Japan, March 20, 1984 (Box 145, f. 27)
    - Business History Seminar: Japan and Reports, April 2, 1984 (Box 145, f. 28)
    - Business History Seminar: Japan #2, April 9, 1984 (Box 145, f. 29)
    - Business History Seminar: Papers and USSR, April 17, 1984 (Box 145, f. 30)
    - Business History Seminar: The Development of the Modern Corporation in Industrial Perspective, Fall 1984 (Box 145, f. 31)
    - Business History Seminar: Lists/Correspondence, Fall 1984 (Box 145, f. 32)
    - Business History Seminar: #2, Fall 1984 (Box 146, f. 1)
    - Business History Seminar: #3, Fall 1984 (Box 146, f. 2)
    - Business History Seminar: #4, Fall 1984 (Box 146, f. 3)
    - Business History Seminar, Oct. 10, 1984 (Box 146, f. 4)
    - Business History Seminar: Jacobs-U.S. Labor, Fall 1984 (Box 146, f. 5)
    - Business History Seminar: U.K., Oct. 24, 1984 (Box 146, f. 6)
    - Business History Seminar: U.K. Labor, 1984 (Box 146, f. 7)
    - Business History Seminar: Germany, 1984 (Box 146, f. 8)
    - Business History Seminar: Course Description, etc., Spring 1985 (Box 146, f. 9)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 16, 1985 (Box 146, f. 10)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 23, 1985 (Box 146, f. 11)
    - Business History Seminar, Jan. 30, 1985 (Box 146, f. 12)
    - Business History Seminar, April 27, 1985 (Box 146, f. 13)
    - Business History Seminar, 1985? (Box 146, f. 14)
    - Business History Seminar, April 9, 1986 (Box 146, f. 15)
    - Business History Seminar, Feb. 5, 1986? (Box 146, f. 16)
    - Business History Course: Notes on the Conglomerates, undated (Box 146, f. 17)
    - Business History Course: Mass Marketing, undated (Box 146, f. 18)
    - Business History Course: Final Day, Dec. 6, 8 undated (Box 146, f. 19)
    - Business History Course: Labor, Oct. 21, 28 undated (Box 147, f. 1)
    - Business History Course: The Depression, undated (Box 147, f. 2)
    - Business History Course: Background to 19th cent. Economy, undated (Box 147, f. 3)
    - Business History Course: Material, undated (Box 147, f. 4-5)
    - Business History Seminar: Competition and Industry Structure, 1986 (Box 147, f. 6)
    - Business History Seminar, 1986 (Box 147, f. 7)
    - Business History Seminar: Technology, competition, and industry structure, 1880-1986, Spring 1987 (Box 237, f. 6-10)
    - Business History Seminar: Technology, The Workplace, and Competition, 1880-1988, Spring 1988 (Box 238, f. 1-3)
    - Business History Seminar: Innovation, Public Policy, and Industrial Structure, Spring 1989 (Box 238, f. 4-5)
    - Business History Seminar: Lecture, undated (Box 147, f. 8)
    - Business History Lecture for Glen Porter, undated (Box 147, f. 9)
    - Annotated Cases (Box 147, f. 10-12)
    - Business History Course Cases (Box 147, f. 13)
    - Case: Revision of Morgan Case, circa 1972 (Box 147, f. 14)
    - Case: Material for G.M. Case, circa 1972 (Box 147, f. 15)
    - Case: Jay Gould and the Coming of Railroad Consolidation: Draft, circa 1972-1973 (Box 147, f. 16)
    - Case: The Spread of Multi-Industry, Multidivisional Enterprise: Draft, 1973 (Box 147, f. 17)
    - Case: The Multinational Enterprise: Draft, 1973 (Box 147, f. 18)
    - Case: The Coming of Modern Management: Draft, 1973 (Box 148, f. 1)
    - Case: The Economic Revolution Completed, circa 1980 (Box 148, f. 2)
    - Case: Alexander Hamilton and the Creation of a National Economy, 1983 (Box 148, f. 3)
    - Business History Cases (Box 148, f. 4)
    - DuPont and G.M.: Lecture Notes, 1980-1983 (Box 148, f. 5)
    - Labor: Lecture Notes, undated (Box 148, f. 6)
    - Workers: Lecture Notes, undated. (Box 148, f. 7)
  - Subseries F. HBS External Activities: Conferences, 1971-1989
    This series consists of material from conferences in which Alfred Chandler was involved as well as talks, lectures, and seminars sponsored by institutions other than Harvard Business School while Chandler was teaching at HBS. The material includes correspondence, comments on papers, preliminary and final drafts of papers by Chandler and others, notes, and research material.
    - OHA: New Orleans, April 1971 (Box 149, f. 1)
    - Business Policy Conference: HBS, May 23-28, 1971 (Box 149, f. 2)
    - Evolution of International Management Structures: Delaware, May 4-6, 1972 (Box 149, f. 3-10)
    - EPA: Presidential Address, 1972 (Box 149, f. 11-18)
    - Multinational Enterprise Project Conference, Jan. 4-5, 1973 (Box 150, f. 1)
    - Rutgers Talk, March 1973 (Box 150, f. 2)
    - Kaplan Lecture: U. of Pennsylvania, April 1973 (Box 150, f. 3)
    - International Conference: Investment Strategy, Leuven, July 1973 (Box 150, f. 4)
    - American Management Association Talk, August 1973 (Box 150, f. 5)
    - International Business History Conference, Japan, Jan. 1974 (Box 150, f. 6-10)
    - Business History Conference: Delaware, March 1974 (Box 150, f. 13-14)
    - International Seminar: Structural and Development Problems: Turin, March 1974 (Box 150, f. 15-18)
    - U.S. Naval College: Senior Officer Management Course, July 19, 1974 (Box 151, f. 1-2)
    - 6th International Congress on Economic History: Copenhagen, Aug. 1974 (Box 151, f. 3)
    - 20th c. Capitalism: Council for European Studies: HBS, Sept. 1974 (Box 151, f. 4-8)
    - International Conference on Business History: Japan, Jan. 1975 (Box 151, f. 9-10)
    - AHA: Presidential Papers: Atlanta, Dec. 1975 (Box 151, f. 11)
    - Oxford Seminar, circa 1975 (Box 151, f. 12)
    - International Symposium: The Evolution of the Corporate Economy, Leuven, Feb. 1976 (Box 151, f. 13)
    - OHA, April 1976 (Box 151, f. 14)
    - Johns Hopkins University: Divestiture in Historical Perspective, May 1976 (Box 151, f. 15)
    - Multinational enterprise Project conference, Jan. 4-5, 1973 (Box 151, f. 16)
    - Conference on American-east Asian Economic Relations: Mt. Kisco, N.Y., June 1976 (Box 151, f. 17-19)
    - Center for Interdisciplinary Research: Bielefeld, July, 1976 (Box 152, f. 1-2)
    - Columbia University: Seminar on Economic History, Jan. 1977 (Box 152, f. 3-4)
    - Seminar: Indiana; Ohio, Feb. 1977 (Box 152, f. 5)
    - Ohio State University, Feb. 1977 (Box 152, f. 6-8)
    - North Carolina State University, April 1977 (Box 152, f. 9-10)
    - Eastern Academy of Management: U.S. Coast Guard Academy, May 1977 (Box 152, f. 11)
    - Board of Anti-trust Forum: New York, May 1977 (Box 152, f. 12)
    - Historical Formation...: Bielefeld, June 1977 (Box 152, f. 13-20)
    - Rise of Modern Business Enterprise...: HBS, Sept. 11-12, 1977 (Box 153, f. 1-6)
    - History of Technology and Society Seminar: Univ. of Pennsylvania, Nov. 1977 (Box 153, f. 7-8)
    - Business History: Wilmington, Del., Feb. 1978 (Box 153, f. 9)
    - The Rise of the American System...Symposium: Smithsonian, March. 1978 (Box 153, f. 10-13)
    - Organization of American Historians: New York, April 1978 (Box 153, f. 14-15)
    - Organization Behavior-Policy: Tuck; Dartmouth, April 1978 (Box 153, f. 16-17)
    - Brown University Lecture, April 24, 1978 (Box 153, f. 18)
    - Harvard University Press Visiting Committee Talk, May 1978 (Box 153, f. 19)
    - International Economic History: Edinburgh, Aug. 1978 (Box 154, f. 1)
    - Harvard Club Talk, Sept. 1978 (Box 154, f. 2)
    - Society for the History of Technology: Meetings: Pittsburgh, Oct. 1978 (Box 154, f. 3)
    - Wellington-Burnham Lecture: Tufts, Oct. 31, 1978 (Box 154, f. 4-5)
    - Public Policy: HBS, Nov. 1978 (Box 154, f. 6-7)
    - U.S./U.S.S.R. Colloquium: Moscow, Nov.-Dec. 1978 (Box 154, f. 8-12)
    - U.S./U.S.S.R. Colloquium: Papers: Moscow, Nov.-Dec. 1978 (Box 154, f. 13-20)
    - MIT/Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique: Paris, Feb. 1979 (Box 155, f. 1-8)
    - Honorary Degree Address: University of Antwerp, March 1979 (Box 155, f. 9)
    - Economics and Business History: London School of Economics, March 1979 (Box 155, f. 10)